<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GDG Bangalore</title>
    <description>Google Developer Group Bangalore</description>
    <link>http://gdgbangalore.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://gdgbangalore.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Explore new Possibilities with GDG Bangalore: Post Google I/O Session</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We conducted this meetup as a follow up of the Google I/O event. We focused on exploring the concepts of Ubiquitous programming and a discussion of web frameworks with Meteor as an example. The idea was to get in touch with developers and explore the eco-system that Google provides. The event was organized on 2nd August, 2014 at the Intel Campus, Bangalore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/106713173238624167691&quot;&gt;Shreyas Kulkarni&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/shreys91/ubiquitous-programming&quot;&gt;Ubiquitous Programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. How was your experience as a speaker at the meetup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The experience was amazing. It was the first time I was speaking at an event related to Google. The event was very well organized, very well coordinated and was almost glitch free. It was a pleasure to be present at an event like this. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. How much exposure do you think people have towards the concept of Ubiquitous programming and why?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ubiquitous Programming (quite an ambiguous name), is in very nascent stages. There is NO documentation yet, there are no fixed rules defined. We just see some small implementations of it in few places. Most of these implementations are cloud centric and don’t tap in the potential and the power of devices local to us. This talk dealt with tapping of such resources and possible changes that can be made into our architectures, so that we exploit the power around us, rather than blindly depending on cloud all the time. Since this was a very nascent topic, a lot of audience seemed to have very less exposure. Also exposure to concepts like Service Oriented Architecture and Functional Programming was limited and hence I had to extemporaneously change the complexity of the presentation and touch upon basics .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What did you like the most during the event ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free Pizza :P .On a serious note, there wasn’t anything much to complain about the event. I would have been happier if the audience consisted of more developers, more folks from the industry - it would have been more apt for an event of such kind. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/shreys91/ubiquitous-programming&quot;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt; to the presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/105273984087201613503&quot;&gt;Priya Arora&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meteor.com/&quot;&gt;Meteor Framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. How was your experience as a speaker at the meetup?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a very nice experience, being my first talk. Got to gain new experiences and how this can be proceeded further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. How has been your experience with Meteor as compared to other frameworks ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meteor framework is very easy to use. In comparison to other frameworks, web applications can easily be built using this framework. One just needs to understand the flow and everything else will be done by the framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What did you like the most during the event?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is nothing that I can complain about. But, more number of experienced developers should be there. The event was pretty organised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you missed the event, you can watch the video here&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/CsyhU3p-3Fs&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2014 15:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://gdgbangalore.github.io//blog/Explore-New-Possibilities</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gdgbangalore.github.io//blog/Explore-New-Possibilities</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Google Cloud Workshop</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We organized a workshop on &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/&quot;&gt;Google Cloud&lt;/a&gt; inviting developers to give them a hands on experience with the Google Cloud Technology on the 7th of June 2014 at Hotel Royal Orchid, Bangalore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/u/0/+ShivamAgarwal404&quot;&gt;Shivam Agarwal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. How was your experience as a Speaker at Google Cloud Workshop?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my first experience as a speaker in a GDG event and I can simply describe it in one word - AWESOME!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. How was the response from the attendees?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attendees were a mixed crowd. One of the problems I faced during the event was that many of the attendees were not prepared i.e. they didn’t have their machines preconfigured according to the instructions which were given earlier. This consumed some time during which more hands on experience was planned. One thing I liked about the attendees was that they were very inquisitive. Their questions covered material which I was going to talk about 4-5 slides ahead. This also created an atmosphere of curiosity to learn and think out of the box. Attendees were from different careers and companies and they shared their experiences while asking questions, which helped in uncovering diverse application areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What did you like the most during the event?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing I liked the most was the amount of energy, dedication and team work of GDG and GSA members to host the event successfully. I am very thankful to GDG Bangalore and Google to give me the opportunity of being a speaker. Thank you guys! GDG Bangalore rocks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/u/0/103302681672889679709&quot;&gt;Satendra Singh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. How was your experience as a Speaker at Google Cloud Workshop?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great experience all together as I got the opportunity to share my knowledge and experience being a part of the developer community of Google App Engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. How was the response from the attendees?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attendees asked quite a lot of technical questions and a variety of questions that made the session more interesting and an extensive exchange of knowledge about various challenges they were facing while implementing their solution on cloud and how Google App Engine could solve their concern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. What did you like the most during the event?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moment I liked the most, was when attendees came forward and discussed their business problems to find the solution through Google App Engine cloud platform and their willingness to know as much as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2014 15:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://gdgbangalore.github.io//blog/Google-Cloud-Workshop</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://gdgbangalore.github.io//blog/Google-Cloud-Workshop</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
